<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>devops on OpsNotice.xyz</title><link>https://valentin2105.github.io/opsnotice.xyz/categories/devops/</link><description>Recent content in devops on OpsNotice.xyz</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 23:22:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://valentin2105.github.io/opsnotice.xyz/categories/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>IPTables IPv4/6 for Docker</title><link>https://valentin2105.github.io/opsnotice.xyz/post/iptables-ferm-docker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 23:22:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://valentin2105.github.io/opsnotice.xyz/post/iptables-ferm-docker/</guid><description>Docker use IPTables to create network isolation between containers, to NAT traffic from their private networks and to expose ports on your Docker host. It&amp;rsquo;s why manage a firewall in front of that is not easy as 1,2,3, even more if you use dual stack (IPv4/6) on your containers.
To facilitate the control of Docker host&amp;rsquo;s firewall, I use Ferm, a great Perl front-end for IPtables. You can for sure use the great and simple UFW but Ferm got a more declarative way to write your firewall rules.</description></item><item><title>Docker with Saltstack</title><link>https://valentin2105.github.io/opsnotice.xyz/post/docker-with-saltstack/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 10:09:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://valentin2105.github.io/opsnotice.xyz/post/docker-with-saltstack/</guid><description>Docker is a fantastic but sometimes container management can be complicated. To simplify and automate Docker application deployments we can use Saltstack, a strong configuration management written in Python and using ZeroMQ for dial with servers (called minions).
In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how-to use Saltstack on a virtual cloud server based on Debian or Ubuntu. Salt will be used in a standalone mode, without master server.
Install Saltstack on your server We&amp;rsquo;re going to install salt-minion who&amp;rsquo;ll manage our deployment.</description></item><item><title>Overview of Rancher UI</title><link>https://valentin2105.github.io/opsnotice.xyz/post/overview-rancher-ui/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 22:09:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://valentin2105.github.io/opsnotice.xyz/post/overview-rancher-ui/</guid><description>Today, I&amp;rsquo;ll introduce you to Rancher UI, a Docker cluster management system, allowing deploy containers across multiple Docker hosts. You can manage your own Docker servers, deploy VMs on the cloud or add your Swarm, Kubernetes or Mesos existent clusters.
Say hello to Rancher, the container management platform that makes everything easy.
The goal of Rancher UI is to manage some Docker hosts (virtual or physical) from a Web interface which ensures container orchestration.</description></item></channel></rss>